<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recent Content on Unit Circle Rekkids </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;about us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unit Circle Rekkids was founded in 1991 by Kevin Goldsmith and is dedicated to releasing new music and sound art that challenges existing conventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;contact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;e-mail
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;table border=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;rek&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;!--Screw you spammers --&gt;
        kids&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;@&lt;!--Screw you spammers --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;unit&lt;!--Screw you spammers --&gt;circle&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;!--Screw you spammers --&gt;.co&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;m&lt;!--Screw you spammers --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;postal mail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  Unit Circle Rekkids&lt;br /&gt;
  PO Box 20352&lt;br /&gt;
    Seattle, WA 98102&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bethany Curve</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/artists/BethanyCurve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 11:33:57 CET</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/artists/BethanyCurve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bethany Curve is Richard Millang on guitar and vocals, David MacWha on drums and Ray Lake on guitar and vocals. They are from Santa Cruz, California. They were formed in 1994. Bethany Curve are Unit Circle&amp;rsquo;s flagship band. Their releases amaze listeners with their craftsmanship and quality. Their motto is &amp;ldquo;Atmosphere, Arrangement, Sound, Layering and Noise.&amp;rdquo; This fits their music exactly and is exactly why we like them so much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intonarumori</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/artists/Intonarumori/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 11:32:28 CET</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/artists/Intonarumori/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kevin Goldsmith has been composing under the name &amp;ldquo;Intonarumori&amp;rdquo; since he studied experimental and electronic composition with composer Reza Vali at Carnegie Mellon University in 1990-2. In addition to composing, Kevin performs on a variety of instruments: Cello, 5 String Electric Cello, Bass Guitar, D-Tar (prepared guitar), Synthesizer and Electronics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word &amp;ldquo;Intonarumori&amp;rdquo; is Italian and it means &amp;ldquo;noise intoners.&amp;rdquo; The word comes from the Italian Futurist art movement. The Intonarumori were machines built to mimic the industrial sounds of the age. The Futurist composers created symphonies for the machines. Their concerts often resulted in fist-fights with the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intonarumori, the project, is very much influenced by the ideas of the Futurists as well as the more modern ideas of the serialists, the minimalists, the musique concrete-ists and modern experimental and industrial composers. Intonarumori performs rarely, but completed a 16 city us tour in the summer of 1998 which included performances with Cul De Sac, Mason Jones, and Ken Vandermark. Kevin&amp;rsquo;s early compositions incorporated many minimalist techniques of repition, blending them with Music Concrete ideas of found sounds and using some of John Cage&amp;rsquo;s chance operation concepts. These compositions were extremely reliant on studio technology to create. In recent years, Intonarumori compositions have become more open and less structured. These compositions create a situation for the performer for which he or she can use any method that they find suitable to resolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Deeply atmospheric collage pieces bear the influence of John Cage and Phillip Glass. Intonarumori&amp;rsquo;s pastiches of electronic noise and classical instruments such as cello and piano create velvety, hallucinatory soundscapes sometimes broken by the inclusion of harsh industrial dissonance. These songs are a disquieting mix of placid pastoralism and icy futurism.&amp;rdquo; - Listen.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intonarumori - L-ST</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC090/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC090/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the 2002 release of Material, Intonarumori&amp;rsquo;s Kevin Goldsmith began looking towards new approaches to composition and ways of producing sound. Having spent more than a decade producing electro-acoustic sounds by combining cello, bass and other instruments with electronic processing and synthesized ambiences into a sometimes sonic overloading wash of sound, what Goldsmith called maximal-minimalism; he wanted to move into more subtler areas. Over the next few years of performing and recording as Intonarumori as well as with transPacifc, he produced several tracks for a drastically different new album from his previous work. After going through the tracks several times, he decided to put the album to the side so that he could come at it with fresh ears. The original plan of waiting a few months became a few years. Finally, in 2013 after a re-location to Europe, Goldsmith returned to those tracks again. With a new critical ear, he pruned mercilessly, adding only those tracks which he felt had stood the test of time. The result is L-ST, a new approach for Intonarumori. A lost album, but something that still sounds vital and contemporary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bethany Curve - You Brought Us Here</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC074/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2001 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC074/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bethany Curve have been long known for their exactness and attention to detail, especially in the studio. For this album, they created their own studio so they could be free of the constraints of the rented studio clock. The result was this album, three years in the making and their most complex and polished to date. Their sound continues to evolve around their atmospheric, soaring style. This album was released on September 4, 2001&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pineal Ventana - Axes to Ice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC067/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2000 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC067/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is Pineal Ventana&amp;rsquo;s second release for Unit Circle Rekkids. The first, Malpractice, was a soaring and driving collection of songs that drove from quiet spaces into walls of screaching noise. This album is a greater exploration of the possibilities of sound. The members of Pineal Ventana stray even further from convention without abandoning what makes their music unique. This is a far scarier record. This CD was released on September 5th, 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Horist - Songs From the Nerve Wheel</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC066/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2000 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC066/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is Bill Horist&amp;rsquo;s second release for Unit Circle Rekkids. His first, Soylent Radio, was an amazing exploration of sonic weirdness translated through wild guitar manipulations. Bill&amp;rsquo;s style grew and his abilities expanded in the three years since Soylent Radio and this record. Bill takes his patented guitar manipulations technique and expands his palette into new soundscapes and more rhythmic and textural possibilities. This CD was released on June 6, 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intonarumori - Intonarumori</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC062/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 1999 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC062/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is Intonarumori&amp;rsquo;s first full length release. It&amp;rsquo;s about frigging time. The project has been around since 1990. This is an unusual album for Intonarumori because it represents material that was all recorded live in concert recorded straight from Intonarumori&amp;rsquo;s board. Listening to the album it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to believe that the first three pieces were all recorded by one person. There are layers and shifting textures, ambiences and spaces. The second half of the album represents a work created for small chamber ensemble (Cello, Violin, Toy Piano, Found Percussion, and two vocalists) to celebrate Paul Celan. A very different sound and very unexpected from Intonarumori. This CD was released on December 21st, 1999.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M&#39;lumbo - Spinning Tourists in a City of Ghosts</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC061/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 1999 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC061/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This album has been a very long time in the making. M&amp;rsquo;lumbo first approached us in 1996 with a tape of an album that they had finished. It was an excellent mix of avant-jazz with world music beats and textures. It captivated us with it&amp;rsquo;s unique sounds. Due to some confusion, that album was eventually released by Staalplaat. It turns out to have been a good thing, because the M&amp;rsquo;lumbo crew put together a whole new album for us that is much much better. They still have elements of world music in their stew, but now it&amp;rsquo;s updated with more electronic sounds and textures. It shows how the band continue to mature and grow and refuse to get stale. This album was released on October 5th, 1999.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amy Denio - Greatest Hits</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC060/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 1999 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC060/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Amy approached us about putting out a Greatest Hits album, we were ecstatic. Amy has produced an amazing amount of excellent music over her career. It was a hard time figuring out which pieces to use. Luckily for us, MØre Music, in Italy, had produced a limited-edition version of a Greatest Hits album and had picked almost the perfect tracks. We augmented their choices with some of our own, including newer material. The result is as much as we could have ever hoped for. A collection of material from an artist with a long and distinguished career that succeeds in showing where she has been and where she is going.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pineal Ventana - Malpractice</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC058/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1999 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC058/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the Unit Circle Debut from Atlanta-based &lt;a href=&#34;../../artists/PinealVentana/&#34;&gt;Pineal Ventana&lt;/a&gt;. It was released in April of 1999. We&amp;rsquo;d been talking with Mitch and Clara for years. It took a while to figure out how we wanted to work together, but this is the fruit of that effort: a super kick-ass record. This album was recorded by Martin Bisi whose production and engineering credits include Sonic Youth, Material, and Michael Gira. Martin Bisi also produced their next album &amp;quot;Axes to Ice&amp;quot; which ended up being their final recording.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupiter 88 - Jupiter 88 EP</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC056/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 1998 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC056/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is the debut EP from the Boston-based duo, &lt;a href=&#34;../../artists/Jupiter88/&#34;&gt;Jupiter 88&lt;/a&gt;. and the only album featuring the original pairing of Darla Villani and Michael MacDonald. Before we released this album, We&amp;rsquo;d been corresponding with them for quite some time. Their music was always good, but we never expected it to be as amazing as this CD is. This was a joint release with their label, Subsonic Records.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UnFolkUs - UnFolkUs</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC055/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 1998 00:00:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC055/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is &lt;a href=&#34;../../artists/UnFolkUs/&#34;&gt;UnFolkUs&amp;rsquo;&lt;/a&gt; first and only release. This Seattle improvisors super group featured Paul Hoskin, Bill Horist, Eveline Muller-Graf and Rob Bageant. The band discovered and explored depths of quietude as deep as their walls of noise were tall (which is not to say that they don&amp;rsquo;t retain a penchant for well-placed sonic assaults).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;quot;UnFolkUs pushes its music through a kaleidoscope of effects, extensions, and extremeties and onto a fresh sonic terrain build out of free jazz and post-classical, contemporary concert music.&amp;quot; - The Stranger. This disc is a joint release between Unit Circle Rekkids and the band.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bethany Curve - Gold</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC046/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 1998 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC046/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is Bethany Curve&amp;rsquo;s second album for the label. This first Skies A Crossed Sky was amazing. This one is better, in fact, it is the best-selling album on the label and was the first Unit Circle release to break into the CMJ top 200.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Horist - Soylent Radio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC045/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 1997 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC045/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first met Bill not long after he arrived in Seattle. He auditioned for a band I was playing in at the time. We were playing straight ahead rock more or less. He came in with this amazingly wild guitar work. All of the place, but not sloppy. He knew exactly what he was doing. He didn&amp;rsquo;t get the gig, mostly because the rest of us doubted that we could keep up with him. I knew that I&amp;rsquo;d met up with a unique talent and kept in touch with him. His first solo release came on the &lt;a href=&#34;../tUC021/&#34; target=&#34;main&#34;&gt;Nocturne Concr&amp;#232;te Compilation&lt;/a&gt; that Unit Circle put out in 1995. He has continued to refine his improv skills by playing with a number of the coolest improv ensembles around the Seattle area, including &lt;a href=&#34;../UnFolkUs&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;UnFolkUs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;b&gt;SpringTrapHum&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;Fin&lt;/b&gt;. Beyond his amazing solo pieces, this CD features some excellent duets with Seattle Area Improvisers Rich Hinklin, Eveline Muller and Troy Swanson. This is Bill&amp;rsquo;s first full-length album, his second &amp;quot;Songs From the Nerve Wheel&amp;quot; was also released by Unit Circle in 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>