<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
      <title>Recent Content on Unit Circle Rekkids </title>
      <generator uri="https://hugo.spf13.com">Hugo</generator>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/index.xml/</link>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
    
    <updated>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</updated>
    
    <item>
      <title>about</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2015 00:00:00 UTC</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_0&#34;&gt;about us&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unit Circle Rekkids was founded in 1991 by Kevin Goldsmith and is dedicated to releasing new music and sound art that challenges existing conventions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;toc_1&#34;&gt;contact&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div id=&#34;contact&#34;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;e-mail
  &lt;/strong&gt;
  &lt;table border=&#34;0&#34; cellpadding=&#34;0&#34; cellspacing=&#34;0&#34;&gt;
    &lt;tr&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;rek&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;!--Screw you spammers --&gt;
        kids&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;@&lt;!--Screw you spammers --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;unit&lt;!--Screw you spammers --&gt;circle&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;&lt;!--Screw you spammers --&gt;.co&lt;/td&gt;
      &lt;td&gt;m&lt;!--Screw you spammers --&gt;&lt;/td&gt;
    &lt;/tr&gt;
  &lt;/table&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;postal mail&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
  Unit Circle Rekkids&lt;br /&gt;
  PO Box 20352&lt;br /&gt;
    Seattle, WA 98102&lt;/p&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bethany Curve</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/artists/BethanyCurve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 11:33:57 CET</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/artists/BethanyCurve/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bethany Curve is Richard Millang on guitar and vocals, David MacWha on drums and Ray Lake on guitar and vocals. They are from Santa Cruz, California. They were formed in 1994. Bethany Curve are Unit Circle&amp;rsquo;s flagship band. Their releases amaze listeners with their craftsmanship and quality. Their motto is &amp;ldquo;Atmosphere, Arrangement, Sound, Layering and Noise.&amp;rdquo; This fits their music exactly and is exactly why we like them so much.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intonarumori</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/artists/Intonarumori/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2014 11:32:28 CET</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/artists/Intonarumori/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Kevin Goldsmith has been composing under the name &amp;ldquo;Intonarumori&amp;rdquo; since he studied experimental and electronic composition with composer Reza Vali at Carnegie Mellon University in 1990-2. In addition to composing, Kevin performs on a variety of instruments: Cello, 5 String Electric Cello, Bass Guitar, D-Tar (prepared guitar), Synthesizer and Electronics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The word &amp;ldquo;Intonarumori&amp;rdquo; is Italian and it means &amp;ldquo;noise intoners.&amp;rdquo; The word comes from the Italian Futurist art movement. The Intonarumori were machines built to mimic the industrial sounds of the age. The Futurist composers created symphonies for the machines. Their concerts often resulted in fist-fights with the audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Intonarumori, the project, is very much influenced by the ideas of the Futurists as well as the more modern ideas of the serialists, the minimalists, the musique concrete-ists and modern experimental and industrial composers. Intonarumori performs rarely, but completed a 16 city us tour in the summer of 1998 which included performances with Cul De Sac, Mason Jones, and Ken Vandermark. Kevin&amp;rsquo;s early compositions incorporated many minimalist techniques of repition, blending them with Music Concrete ideas of found sounds and using some of John Cage&amp;rsquo;s chance operation concepts. These compositions were extremely reliant on studio technology to create. In recent years, Intonarumori compositions have become more open and less structured. These compositions create a situation for the performer for which he or she can use any method that they find suitable to resolve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;ldquo;Deeply atmospheric collage pieces bear the influence of John Cage and Phillip Glass. Intonarumori&amp;rsquo;s pastiches of electronic noise and classical instruments such as cello and piano create velvety, hallucinatory soundscapes sometimes broken by the inclusion of harsh industrial dissonance. These songs are a disquieting mix of placid pastoralism and icy futurism.&amp;rdquo; - Listen.com&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intonarumori - L-ST</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC090/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC090/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Following the 2002 release of Material, Intonarumori&amp;rsquo;s Kevin Goldsmith began looking towards new approaches to composition and ways of producing sound. Having spent more than a decade producing electro-acoustic sounds by combining cello, bass and other instruments with electronic processing and synthesized ambiences into a sometimes sonic overloading wash of sound, what Goldsmith called maximal-minimalism; he wanted to move into more subtler areas. Over the next few years of performing and recording as Intonarumori as well as with transPacifc, he produced several tracks for a drastically different new album from his previous work. After going through the tracks several times, he decided to put the album to the side so that he could come at it with fresh ears. The original plan of waiting a few months became a few years. Finally, in 2013 after a re-location to Europe, Goldsmith returned to those tracks again. With a new critical ear, he pruned mercilessly, adding only those tracks which he felt had stood the test of time. The result is L-ST, a new approach for Intonarumori. A lost album, but something that still sounds vital and contemporary.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bethany Curve - You Brought Us Here</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC074/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2001 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC074/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bethany Curve have been long known for their exactness and attention to detail, especially in the studio. For this album, they created their own studio so they could be free of the constraints of the rented studio clock. The result was this album, three years in the making and their most complex and polished to date. Their sound continues to evolve around their atmospheric, soaring style. This album was released on September 4, 2001&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bethany Curve - Gold</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC046/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 1998 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC046/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is Bethany Curve&amp;rsquo;s second album for the label. This first Skies A Crossed Sky was amazing. This one is better, in fact, it is the best-selling album on the label and was the first Unit Circle release to break into the CMJ top 200.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Horist - Soylent Radio</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC045/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 1997 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC045/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I first met Bill not long after he arrived in Seattle. He auditioned for a band I was playing in at the time. We were playing straight ahead rock more or less. He came in with this amazingly wild guitar work. All of the place, but not sloppy. He knew exactly what he was doing. He didn&amp;rsquo;t get the gig, mostly because the rest of us doubted that we could keep up with him. I knew that I&amp;rsquo;d met up with a unique talent and kept in touch with him. His first solo release came on the &lt;a href=&#34;../tUC021/&#34; target=&#34;main&#34;&gt;Nocturne Concr&amp;#232;te Compilation&lt;/a&gt; that Unit Circle put out in 1995. He has continued to refine his improv skills by playing with a number of the coolest improv ensembles around the Seattle area, including &lt;a href=&#34;../UnFolkUs&#34;&gt;&lt;b&gt;UnFolkUs&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, &lt;b&gt;SpringTrapHum&lt;/b&gt;, and &lt;b&gt;Fin&lt;/b&gt;. Beyond his amazing solo pieces, this CD features some excellent duets with Seattle Area Improvisers Rich Hinklin, Eveline Muller and Troy Swanson. This is Bill&amp;rsquo;s first full-length album, his second &amp;quot;Songs From the Nerve Wheel&amp;quot; was also released by Unit Circle in 2000.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SubArachnoid Space - Ether Or</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC041/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 1997 12:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC041/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When Mason gave me a chance to put out SubArachnoid Space&amp;rsquo;s second CD (their first was on Charnel House), I jumped at the chance. SAS&amp;rsquo; music is sometimes wild, sometimes subtle, but always interesting. Even more interesting when you consider that ALL of it is improvised. I was given a ton of material that the band had recorded, and I selected a set of pieces that I thought fit well withing the Unit Circle&amp;rsquo;s roster. The work presented on this disc is slightly more ponderous and dark, but it still shows their range as a unique ensemble.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tUC034</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC034/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 1996 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC034/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Bethany Curve&amp;rsquo;s first, self-produced, album came in while preparation was underway for Nocturne Concrète. It was frankly amazing. Probably the best demo tape we&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard. They became the first band to officially &amp;ldquo;sign&amp;rdquo; with Unit Circle Rekkids. They followed up this great record with the stellar &amp;ldquo;Gold&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;You Brought Us Here&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tUC021</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 1996 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC021/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Nocturne Concrète was our first CD. We gathered together 13 of our favorite bands crossing all the genres that we hoped to represent on the label. This album spans electronic, ambient, experiment, gothic and avant-rock genres.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tUC018</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 1995 11:42:21 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Released in 1995, this is Intonarumori&amp;rsquo;s first full-length release. It collects many of Intonarumori&amp;rsquo;s early sound collage pieces together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tUC015</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 1995 10:15:39 &#43;0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC015/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Garden have been playing around Pittsburgh, PA since the mid-eighties. They have done several amazing self-produced cassettes, but had never been released on another label. We wanted to get the word out about them, because they deserve it.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tUC013</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 1995 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/releases/tUC013/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This was Seattle based Vassily&amp;rsquo;s first and last release. It came out in June of 1995 as an edition of 500 and will not be reprinted. It was released in 1995 was Unit Circle&amp;rsquo;s first release in Seattle.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>