<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Releases on Unit Circle Rekkids</title>
    <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Releases on Unit Circle Rekkids</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Answers to April - Lilium EP</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC091/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC091/</guid>
      <description>Reich-like was the first Answers to April track recorded so long ago, I don&amp;rsquo;t even remember when it was. I knew I had something I liked, but it was so different than everything else I was doing, I didn&amp;rsquo;t know what I wanted to do with it.
After moving from Seattle to Sweden in 2013, I found myself wanting to move in a different direction than my Intonarumori work. I have been doing that project for over 25 years.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intonarumori - L-ST</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC090/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Sep 2013 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC090/</guid>
      <description>Following the 2002 release of Material, Intonarumori&amp;rsquo;s Kevin Goldsmith began looking towards new approaches to composition and ways of producing sound. Having spent more than a decade producing electro-acoustic sounds by combining cello, bass and other instruments with electronic processing and synthesized ambiences into a sometimes sonic overloading wash of sound, what Goldsmith called maximal-minimalism; he wanted to move into more subtler areas. Over the next few years of performing and recording as Intonarumori as well as with transPacifc, he produced several tracks for a drastically different new album from his previous work.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupiter 88 - Red Go</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC081/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2003 07:47:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC081/</guid>
      <description>Michael MacDonald, founder and leading force behind Jupiter 88 died unexpectedly in April of 2000. He had already completed recordings for the band&amp;rsquo;s second CD, RedGo. The material for this CD was recorded in 2 different studios - in 2 different incarnations of the band. The original band was predominantly made up of Michael and vocalist Darla Villani. They produced the band&amp;rsquo;s first CD, Jupiter 88, which was released by Unit Circle Rekkids in 1998.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intonarumori - Material</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC075/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 May 2002 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC075/</guid>
      <description>A collection of rare tracks from Intonarumori collected over the last ten years. Includes unreleased tracks and music previously released only on compilations and cassettes or as soundtracks for theater and film productions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bethany Curve - You Brought Us Here</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC074/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Sep 2001 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC074/</guid>
      <description>Bethany Curve have been long known for their exactness and attention to detail, especially in the studio. For this album, they created their own studio so they could be free of the constraints of the rented studio clock. The result was this album, three years in the making and their most complex and polished to date. Their sound continues to evolve around their atmospheric, soaring style. This album was released on September 4, 2001</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Degenerate Art Ensemble - Rinko</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC073/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2001 00:00:30 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC073/</guid>
      <description>Formerly known as The Young Composers Collective, Seattle&amp;rsquo;s Degenerate Art Ensemble continue to amaze with their blending of modern classical music with Asian and experimental influences. From Zorn-style avant-jazz crazyness to Boredoms-esqe noise attacks with a stopover in Stockhausen country, this album is absolutely worth delving into.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tUC069</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC069/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Oct 2000 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC069/</guid>
      <description>After five years of releasing CDs, we realized that people would know about one or two of the bands on the Label, but not the others. To rectify the situation, we asked all of the bands on the label to contribute a track to a new compilation that we could give away super cheap. This is the result, six brand new tracks and one classic from almost all of your favorite Unit Circle groups (the only one we missed was UnFolkUs).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tUC068</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC068/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2000 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC068/</guid>
      <description>I was lucky enough to attend the primeire of Tattoo by the Pat Graney Dance Company in Seattle in the fall of 1999. The piece is a stunning work in all aspects, especially the score by Amy Denio. I&amp;rsquo;d been thinking for a long time that I wanted Unit Circle to start doing a soundtrack series. I wasn&amp;rsquo;t interested in doing traditional soundtracks though. Soundtracks currently dominate the music market and feature films are frequently viewed as a venue for selling soundtrack CDs first.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pineal Ventana - Axes to Ice</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC067/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Sep 2000 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC067/</guid>
      <description>This is Pineal Ventana&amp;rsquo;s second release for Unit Circle Rekkids. The first, Malpractice, was a soaring and driving collection of songs that drove from quiet spaces into walls of screaching noise. This album is a greater exploration of the possibilities of sound. The members of Pineal Ventana stray even further from convention without abandoning what makes their music unique. This is a far scarier record. This CD was released on September 5th, 2000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Horist - Songs From the Nerve Wheel</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC066/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Jun 2000 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC066/</guid>
      <description>This is Bill Horist&amp;rsquo;s second release for Unit Circle Rekkids. His first, Soylent Radio, was an amazing exploration of sonic weirdness translated through wild guitar manipulations. Bill&amp;rsquo;s style grew and his abilities expanded in the three years since Soylent Radio and this record. Bill takes his patented guitar manipulations technique and expands his palette into new soundscapes and more rhythmic and textural possibilities. This CD was released on June 6, 2000.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Intonarumori - Intonarumori</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC062/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Dec 1999 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC062/</guid>
      <description>This is Intonarumori&amp;rsquo;s first full length release. It&amp;rsquo;s about frigging time. The project has been around since 1990. This is an unusual album for Intonarumori because it represents material that was all recorded live in concert recorded straight from Intonarumori&amp;rsquo;s board. Listening to the album it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to believe that the first three pieces were all recorded by one person. There are layers and shifting textures, ambiences and spaces. The second half of the album represents a work created for small chamber ensemble (Cello, Violin, Toy Piano, Found Percussion, and two vocalists) to celebrate Paul Celan.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>M&#39;lumbo - Spinning Tourists in a City of Ghosts</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC061/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Oct 1999 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC061/</guid>
      <description>This album has been a very long time in the making. M&amp;rsquo;lumbo first approached us in 1996 with a tape of an album that they had finished. It was an excellent mix of avant-jazz with world music beats and textures. It captivated us with it&amp;rsquo;s unique sounds. Due to some confusion, that album was eventually released by Staalplaat. It turns out to have been a good thing, because the M&amp;rsquo;lumbo crew put together a whole new album for us that is much much better.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amy Denio - Greatest Hits</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC060/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 May 1999 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC060/</guid>
      <description>When Amy approached us about putting out a Greatest Hits album, we were ecstatic. Amy has produced an amazing amount of excellent music over her career. It was a hard time figuring out which pieces to use. Luckily for us, MØre Music, in Italy, had produced a limited-edition version of a Greatest Hits album and had picked almost the perfect tracks. We augmented their choices with some of our own, including newer material.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pineal Ventana - Malpractice</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC058/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 Apr 1999 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC058/</guid>
      <description>This is the Unit Circle Debut from Atlanta-based Pineal Ventana. It was released in April of 1999. We&amp;rsquo;d been talking with Mitch and Clara for years. It took a while to figure out how we wanted to work together, but this is the fruit of that effort: a super kick-ass record. This album was recorded by Martin Bisi whose production and engineering credits include Sonic Youth, Material, and Michael Gira. Martin Bisi also produced their next album &amp;quot;Axes to Ice&amp;quot; which ended up being their final recording.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Jupiter 88 - Jupiter 88 EP</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC056/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Sep 1998 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC056/</guid>
      <description>This is the debut EP from the Boston-based duo, Jupiter 88. and the only album featuring the original pairing of Darla Villani and Michael MacDonald. Before we released this album, We&amp;rsquo;d been corresponding with them for quite some time. Their music was always good, but we never expected it to be as amazing as this CD is. This was a joint release with their label, Subsonic Records.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UnFolkUs - UnFolkUs</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC055/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 1998 00:00:01 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC055/</guid>
      <description>This is UnFolkUs&amp;rsquo; first and only release. This Seattle improvisors super group featured Paul Hoskin, Bill Horist, Eveline Muller-Graf and Rob Bageant. The band discovered and explored depths of quietude as deep as their walls of noise were tall (which is not to say that they don&amp;rsquo;t retain a penchant for well-placed sonic assaults).
&amp;quot;UnFolkUs pushes its music through a kaleidoscope of effects, extensions, and extremeties and onto a fresh sonic terrain build out of free jazz and post-classical, contemporary concert music.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bethany Curve - Gold</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC046/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 May 1998 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC046/</guid>
      <description>This is Bethany Curve&amp;rsquo;s second album for the label. This first Skies A Crossed Sky was amazing. This one is better, in fact, it is the best-selling album on the label and was the first Unit Circle release to break into the CMJ top 200.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bill Horist - Soylent Radio</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC045/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 1997 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC045/</guid>
      <description>I first met Bill not long after he arrived in Seattle. He auditioned for a band I was playing in at the time. We were playing straight ahead rock more or less. He came in with this amazingly wild guitar work. All of the place, but not sloppy. He knew exactly what he was doing. He didn&amp;rsquo;t get the gig, mostly because the rest of us doubted that we could keep up with him.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SubArachnoid Space - Ether Or</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC041/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Mar 1997 12:01:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC041/</guid>
      <description>When Mason gave me a chance to put out SubArachnoid Space&amp;rsquo;s second CD (their first was on Charnel House), I jumped at the chance. SAS&amp;rsquo; music is sometimes wild, sometimes subtle, but always interesting. Even more interesting when you consider that ALL of it is improvised. I was given a ton of material that the band had recorded, and I selected a set of pieces that I thought fit well withing the Unit Circle&amp;rsquo;s roster.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tUC034</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC034/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 1996 12:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC034/</guid>
      <description>Bethany Curve&amp;rsquo;s first, self-produced, album came in while preparation was underway for Nocturne Concrète. It was frankly amazing. Probably the best demo tape we&amp;rsquo;ve ever heard. They became the first band to officially &amp;ldquo;sign&amp;rdquo; with Unit Circle Rekkids. They followed up this great record with the stellar &amp;ldquo;Gold&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;You Brought Us Here&amp;rdquo;.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tUC021</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC021/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Mar 1996 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC021/</guid>
      <description>Nocturne Concrète was our first CD. We gathered together 13 of our favorite bands crossing all the genres that we hoped to represent on the label. This album spans electronic, ambient, experiment, gothic and avant-rock genres.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tUC018</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC018/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 01 Sep 1995 11:42:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC018/</guid>
      <description>Released in 1995, this is Intonarumori&amp;rsquo;s first full-length release. It collects many of Intonarumori&amp;rsquo;s early sound collage pieces together.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tUC015</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC015/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 1995 10:15:39 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC015/</guid>
      <description>The Garden have been playing around Pittsburgh, PA since the mid-eighties. They have done several amazing self-produced cassettes, but had never been released on another label. We wanted to get the word out about them, because they deserve it.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>tUC013</title>
      <link>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC013/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 1995 00:00:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://unitcircle.com/rekkids/releases/tUC013/</guid>
      <description>This was Seattle based Vassily&amp;rsquo;s first and last release. It came out in June of 1995 as an edition of 500 and will not be reprinted. It was released in 1995 was Unit Circle&amp;rsquo;s first release in Seattle.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>